# **CURRICULUM VITAE**

# **Weiguo Huang**

Industry: Software development

• Address: Timperley, Altrincham, WA15 7GH

**Email**: <u>timhung1221@gmail.com</u>

in Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/weiguo-h-7976a4128

**Gender:** Male **Birth:** Nov. 1969

**Ethnic:** Chinese **Work permit:** UK Citizen

English level: B1 (Intermediate)

#### Personal statement

I used to work in computer software development in China for 13 years, familiar with C# and SQL Server development and workflows. I am adaptable to both team and individual development work and enjoy using C# for development tasks. Through research, I found that almost all higher-level software functions can be solved using C#. After coming to the UK in 2008, I did not continue in software development due to various reasons. In the past two years, I have participated in software training, learned Python, and also relearned HTML, JavaScript, and ASP.NET, obtaining a certificate. I am now looking for a job in software development. If it's C# Windows Desktop development, I can directly take on the role. If it's C# ASP.NET API related work, I'd need short-term training before starting the job.

# **Key Skills**

4 years C# experience,

2 years SQL/Oracle experience,

4 years VB5 experience,

1 year VC++ experience,

1 year C experience.

Python/HTML/JavaScript/Web Apps with ASP.NET Certificated

#### **Personal Characteristics**

I am an excellent team worker and am able to take instructions from all levels and build up good working relationships with all colleagues. I am flexible, reliable and possess excellent time keeping skills. I am an enthusiastic, self-motivated, reliable, responsible and hard-working person. I have a passion for software development work. I am currently seeking an opportunity to join a company that can help me enhance my software development skills, deepen my knowledge, and realize my potential.

## **Available**

1 month.

# **Employment History**

Date: July. 2024 – Present Organization: AOKAI UK LTD

Job Title: Warehouse and logistics admin Resp./Skills: Warehouse management

**Date:** Apr. 2022 – June. 2024

Organization: Hyperiondev, freeCodeCamp, codecademy

Job Title: Student

Resp./Skills: Software development skill learning

Python and SQLite

- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures
- Scientific Computing with Python
- Responsive Web Design
- Front End Development Libraries
- React Basic
- Build Web Apps with ASP.NET Skill Path

Date: Jan. 2021 – Apr. 2022 Organization: AS UK logistic Ltd. (UK)

Job Title: Supervisor

Resp./Skills: Warehouse work

Date: Nov. 2018 – Dec. 2020
Organization: AS UK logistic Ltd. (UK)
Job Title: Worker (Part time)
Resp./Skills: Warehouse work

Date: Sep. 2017 – Oct. 2018
Organization: Tom JL Ltd. (UK)
Job Title: Inventory supervisor
Resp./Skills: Inventory management

Date: Jun. 2016 – Aug. 2017
Organization: Warrantec Company (UK)
Job Title: Inventory supervisor
Resp./Skills: Inventory management

**Date:** Sep. 2015 – May. 2016

Organization: Manchester adult learning center

Job Title: Student

Resp./Skills: ESOL (English for Speakers of Other Languages) learning, Level Entry 3

**Date:** Jul. 2013 – Mar. 2015 **Organization:** Taylor research Ltd. (UK)

Job Title: SEO maintenance

Resp./Skills: Search engines optimization, Wordpress website maintenance

Date: Sep. 2009 – Feb. 2013
Organization: Shulan UK Ltd. (UK)
Job Title: Warehouse supervisor
Resp./Skills: Inventory management

**Date:** Nov 2006 – Oct 2008

Organization: Jerit Tech. Ltd. (Chengdu city, China)

Job Title: Team leader/Software developer

Resp./Skills:

- Software development in C# and VB5(ocx control)
- Windows desktop software design/test/release
- OOP
- Web applications (ASP.NET) development
- Systems analysis/design(Software & Database)/test/release
- Software development life cycle
- Source version control (Microsoft Visual SourceSafe)
- Database maintenance (MS SQL 2000/2005 & Oracle 9i)
- Generation PDF
- Develop tools: VB6, C# 2005, SQL Server 2000/2005, Oracle 9i.

**Date:** Jul 2005 – Oct 2006

Organization: BaiBei Science Tech. Ltd(Chengdu, China)

Job Title: Team leader/Software development

Resp./Skills:

- Software development in C#/VB.NET
- Systems analysis
- Web applications (ASP.NET)
- OCR tech application
- Data upload
- Scan Driver
- Develop tools: C++, VB.NET/C# 2003/2005, SQL Server 2000.

**Date:** Mar. 2005 – Jun. 2005

Organization: ChengDu Summit Softwear Co Ltd. (China)

Job Title: Software Engineer/Development Team Leader

Resp./Skills:

- Development management
- Requirements capture
- Systems analysis
- Systems design (Software)
- Software test
- Recruitment
- Develop tools: VB.NET/C#Net 2005/VC 6, SQL Server 2000, Pocket PC.

**Date:** Mar. 1998 – Jun. 2003

Organization: HuaZhenLian Industry Company (China)

Job Title: Software Engineer/Development Team Leader

## Resp./Skills:

- Development management
- Requirements capture
- Systems analysis/design/test
- Windows desktop software design
- Develop tools: VC6/VB4/VB6 SQL Server 2000, Oracle 7.

**Date:** Jul. 1997 – Feb. 1998

Organization: ChuangLiHeng communication Tec. Ltd. (China)

Job Title: Software Engineer

Resp./Skills:

• Software Programming for DLL.

Software Testing

Develop tools: VC4, SQL server 7.

Date: Mar. 1995 – Jun. 1997 Organization: Group Sense (HK)

Job Title: Assistant Software Engineer

Resp./Skills:

• Embed programming for electronic dictionary

• Develop tools: Borland C/C++ 3.0

#### **Education**

Sep. 1990 – Jul. 1993 – Three years college diploma Economic Management Sichuan University, China

Sep. 1984 – Jul. 1987 – Technical school

Computer Science Application Computer Profession School, China

#### Certificate

May. 2022 - Dec. 2023 Org: Codecademy

Certification type: Single Subject Certification

Items:

Learn React,

Build Web Apps with ASP.NET Skill Path

Apr. 2022 - Dec. 2023 Org: freeCodeCamp

Certification type: Single Subject Certification

Items:

Scientific Computing with Python

- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures
- Responsive Web Design
- Front End Development Libraries

Nov. 2022 - Apr. 2023

Org: HyperionDev & The University of Manchester Certification type: Software Engineering Certificated

Items:

Python science application

Sep. 2015 - May. 2016

Org: Manchester Adult Learning Centre
Certification type: Single Subject Certification

Items: ESOL (English for Speakers of Other Languages)

ESOL Entry 3 Writing & Reading

ESOL Entry 2 Listening

Mar. 2004 - Mar. 2005

Org: NIIT (National Institute Of Information Technology), China

Certification type: Software Engineering Certificated

Items:

- HTML
- CSS
- JAVA
- J2EE
- C#
- SQL

Nov. 2000 – Apr. 2001 Org: SCO, China

Certification type: Software Engineering Certificated

Items:

**UNIX** 

## **Hobbies & Interests**

Swimming, Hiking, Reading, Computer skill, Al skill

## References

- Certificate
- Windows Desktop App Demo
- Python App Demo
- ❖ HTML Demo
- JavaScript Demo

#### **Certificated:**

















